Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings, circa 1966-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Cassette tapes, circa 1966-1993, II.; Tape 53-87; All cassettes stored in one flat container.
  - Cassette tapes of compositions by Morton Feldman, 1967-1987, II.A; Tape 53-71
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 53, undated, 1 cassette; BASF 60 CR-E-II; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown Probably same performance as Tape 54. (Box 05, Item 53)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_53_01
      Coptic light
      Duration: 30:58
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 54, 20 June 1987, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII 60; Performers: Nederlands Philharmonisch Orkest; Koor Nieuwe Muziek; Huub Kerstens, conductor Location of performance: Middelburg (Netherlands) Performers and date from program in Feldman papers (Box 05, Item 54)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_54_01
      Duration: 22:17
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 55, undated, 1 cassette; TKD SA-60; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown Probably same performance as Tape 53 and 54 but tape begins with applause and there is more space before the work begins. (Box 05, Item 55)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_55_01
      Duration: 31:37
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 56, undated, 1 cassette; TKD D60; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown Divided into two files (Box 05, Item 56)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_56_01
      Duration: 90:18
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 57, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell UR90; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown Feldman work on Side B. Side A is labeled Schoenberg: Moses and Aron (Box 05, Item 57)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_57_01
      Duration: 19:00
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_57_02
      Schoenberg, Arnold
      Moses und Aron (incomplete)
      Duration: 47:14
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 58, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII 90; Performers: Erik Skjoldan, piano Location of performance: Unknown Issued by Universal Edition Divided into two files (Box 05, Item 58)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_58_01
      For Bunita Marcus
      Duration: 82:47
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 59, undated, 1 cassette; TDK SA90; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 59)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_59_01
      For Samuel Beckett
      Duration: 57:29
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 60, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII-S 90; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 60)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_60_01
      For Stefan Wolpe
      Duration: 36:00
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 61, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell UR90; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown Marked "good performance (unknown)" (Box 05, Item 61)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_61_01
      Duration: 4:19
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_61_02
      False relationships and the extended ending (rehearsal)
      Feldman can be heard speaking, asking to repeat a section at 10:47.
      Duration: 13:00
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 62, 18 September 1976, 1 cassette; No marking; Performers: Scottish National Orchestra; Elgar Howarth, conductor Location of performance: Glasgow Label on spine: David W. Maves Concerto for 2 pianos & Orch. Appollinaire song World premiere performance; duplicate of Reel to reel tape 24 Same performance recorded two times (Box 05, Item 62)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_62_01
      Duration: 18:18
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_62_02
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 63, 20 November 1986, 1 cassette; TDK SA90; Dolby B; Location of performance: Unknown Label on spine: Salon concert, Clementi's Feldman work on Side B. (Box 05, Item 63)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_63_01
      Music for six
      Duration: 30:40
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_63_02
      Palais de Mari
      Performer: Bunita Marcus, piano
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_63_03
      Wolff, Christian
      Bowery preludes
      Duration: 15:34
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 64, 22 June 1987, 1 cassette; TDK SA90; Dolby B; Performers: Bunita Marcus, piano Location of performance: New York (N.Y.) Side A: 1st version: "Strong -- Mellow"; Side B: Version #2: "Volatile" (Box 05, Item 64)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_64_01
      Duration: 26:22
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_64_02
      Duration: 26:17
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 65, 28 August 1980, 1 cassette; Maxell UD90; Location of performance: London (England) Date from Reel Tape 30 - this is likely a duplicate but not the Schoenberg Feldman work on Side B. (Box 05, Item 65)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_65_01
      Piano concerto
      Performers: Roger Woodward, piano; BBC Scottish Symphony Orchestra; Lawrence Foster, conductor
      Duration: 20:51
      Recording date: 4 August 1979
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_65_02
      Liszt, Franz
      Totentanz
      Duration: 17:33
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_65_03
      Duration: 21:57
      Recording date: 28 August 1980
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_65_04
      Unidentified work for orchestra
      Duration: 14:27
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 66, 2 November 1985, 1 cassette; TDK SF90; Performers: Aki Takahashi, piano; Kronos Quartet Location of performance: Bing Theatre, Los Angeles (Calif.) Marked: "Tape defective - radio stations overlap" Divided into two files (Box 05, Item 66)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_66_01
      Piano and string quartet
      Duration: 77:23
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 67, 4 February 1967, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII90; Two pieces for 3 pianos is duplicate of performance on Reel Tape 32 (Box 05, Item 67)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_67_01
      Two pieces for three pianos
      Performers: Neely Bruce, Dennis Kam, Morton Feldman, pianos
      Recording date: 4 February 1967
      Duration: 14:42
      Location of performance: University of Illinois Festival of Contemporary Arts
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_67_02
      Performers: Swiss Italian Radio (Radiotelevisione svizzera di lingua italiana); Marc Andreae, conductor
      Recording date: March 1981
      Duration: 29:34
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 68, 17 May 1986?, 1 cassette; Sony UCX60; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 68)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_68_01
      Duration: 31:05
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 69, undated, 1 cassette; TDK AD-X90; Performers: Simon Rowland-Jones, viola; John Scott, celeste; Terence Emery, Charles Fulbrook, percussion; Sarah Leonard, soprano; BBC Singers; Simon Joly, conductor Location of performance: St. Alban's Church (Holborn, London) Issued by Universal Edition (Box 05, Item 69)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_69_01
      Duration: 25:13
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 70, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII90; Cello and orchestra performance is duplicate of Reel Tape 1; Kagel performance is duplicate of Reel Tape 37 and 38 (Box 05, Item 70)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_70_01
      Performers: possibly Henri Pousseur, conductor
      Preceded by French announcer
      Duration: 6:05
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_70_02
      Performers: Jules Eskin, cello; Boston Symphony Orchestra, Michael Tilson Thomas, conductor
      Preceded by introduction by Michael Tilson Thomas (2:11)
      Recording date: 25 January 1974
      Duration: 25:42
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_70_03
      Performers: Mauricio Kagel, conductor
      Duration: 5:23
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_70_04
      Performers: possibly Mauricio Kagel, conductor
      Duration: 6:12
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 71, undated, 1 cassette; TDK SA-C90; Dolby C; Performers: Aki Takahashi, piano Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 71)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_71_01
      Triadic memories
      Duration: 1:01:03
  - Cassette tapes of events concerning or with Morton Feldman, 1966-1993, II.B; Tape 72-78
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 72, July 1966, 1 cassette; TDK SA-X60; Performers: John Cage and Morton Feldman in conversation Location of performance: New York (N.Y.) Duplicate of Reel Tape 41-42 (Box 05, Item 72)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_72_01
      Radio happening I
      Duration: 45:17
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 73, 12 September 1966, 1 cassette; TDK SA-X60; Performers: John Cage and Morton Feldman in conversation Location of performance: New York (N.Y.) Duplicate of Reel Tape 43-44 (Box 05, Item 73)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_73_01
      Radio happening II
      Duration: 55:14
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 74, 4 September 1987, 1 cassette; Performers: Peter Whorf, radio host Location of performance: New York (N.Y.) Issued by Universal Edition (Box 05, Item 74)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_74_01
      WNYC-FM radio show "Morning edition" piece on the death of Morton Feldman, including interview segments with John Cage, Bunita Marcus, and Christian Wolff
      Duration: 5:08
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 75, 9 September 1987, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII90; Performers: Speakers include Bunita Marcus, Howie Kanowitz, Nils Vigeland, David Shapiro, Christian Wolff, Brian O'Daugherty, Steve Sloman, Dore Ashton Location of performance: St. Marks Cathedral, New York (N.Y.) (Box 05, Item 75)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_75_01
      Memorial service for Morton Feldman at St. Mark's in New York City
      Duration: 1:09:43
      Divided into two files
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_75_02
      WNYC-FM radio show "Morning edition", hosted by Peter Whorf, piece on the death of Morton Feldman, including interview segments with John Cage, Bunita Marcus, and Christian Wolff
      Duration: 5:16
      Duplicate of Tape 74
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 76-77, 7 November 1987, 2 cassettes; Maxell XLII90; Location of performance: New York (N.Y.) (Box 05, Item 76-77)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_76_01--ubmu0002_2_77_01
      Dreier, Ruth and Whorf, Peter
      WNYC radio show tribute to Morton Feldman, part 1-2
      Duration: 2:57:35
      Includes performance of Feldman's Oboe and orchestra, Palais de Marais (performed by Bunita Marcus), comments by William Colleran, recordings of Artur Rubinstein performing Chopin mazurkas, and a recording of the second movement of a Sibelius symphony.
      Divided into four files
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 78, 16 June 1993, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII90; Location of performance: Buffalo (N.Y.) "The interview took place on Wednesday 16 June 1993 at 4 P.M. in the Buffalo, New York home of Jan Williams (only the first 45 minutes were recorded on tape). Among other things, Williams indicates when Feldman began to collect rugs." (Box 05, Item 78)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_77_01
      Interview of Jan Williams by Sebastian Claren on subject of Morton Feldman
      Duration: 46:41
  - Cassette tapes of compositions by other composers, circa 1974-1986, II.C; Tape 79-87
    Arranged alphabetically by composer's surname and then by the title of the first composition on the tape or a supplied collective title.
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 79, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell XLII90; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 79)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_79_01
      Alrich, Alexis
      Variations for two pianos, from Oakland variations
      Duration: 5:34
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_79_02
      Prelude and jig for mandolin and guitar
      Duration: 9:19
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_79_03
      Set for piano
      Duration: 17:23
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_79_04
      "Water" from the Four elements
      Duration: 7:26
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_79_05
      Lento from Trio for violin, cello, and piano
      Duration: 3:20
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 80, undated, 1 cassette; Realistic Supertape 60; Dolby B; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 80)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_80_01
      Feldman, Barbara Monk
      Variations for six string instruments
      Duration: 24:57
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_80_02
      Trio for violin, cello, and piano
      Duration: 13:57
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 81, undated, 1 cassette; Memorex MRXI 60; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 81)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_81_01
      Nam, Inhwa
      Music for violin and piano
      Duration: 10:25
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 82, undated, 1 cassette; Dolby B; Performers: Unidentified Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 82)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_82_01
      Adam and Eve
      Duration: 36:26
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 83, 1985, 1 cassette; TDK D60 (Box 05, Item 83)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_83_01
      Lecture for Jo Kondo
      Location of performance: California Institute of the Arts
      Duration: 21:02
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_83_02
      Solo (for flute)
      Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute
      Recording date: 1985
      Location of performance: Berlin
      Duration: 27:11
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 84, 5 July 1986, 1 cassette (Box 05, Item 84)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_84_01
      Rugmaker
      Performers: Kronos Quartet
      Location of performance: Middelburg (Netherlands)
      Duration: 19:08
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_84_02
      Performers: UC San Diego Faculty, Bunita Marcus, conductor
      Recording date: April 1986
      Duration: 15:12
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 85, 7 April 1984, 1 cassette; Maxell ULII90; Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute Location of performance: Buffalo (N.Y.) (Box 05, Item 85)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_85_01
      Duration: 42:34
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 86, 2 April 1986, 1 cassette; Dolby B; Performers: Bunita Marcus, lecturer Location of performance: San Diego (Calif.) (Box 05, Item 86)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_86_01
      Lecture on Morton Feldman's "Sound-mass"
      Duration: 49:23
    - Morton Feldman Collection of Audio Recordings Tape 87, undated, 1 cassette; Maxell P/I 60; Performers: SMCQ (Société de musique contemporaine du Québec); Serge Garant, conductor Location of performance: Unknown (Box 05, Item 87)
      Work number: ubmu0002_2_87_01
      Rea, John
      Treppenmusik
      Duration: 16:21
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--20th century; Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987--Archives
Genres
Sound recordings; Audiocassettes; Audiotapes
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
Mus. Arc. 2.1
The Morton Feldman Papers comprise personal and business correspondence, writings by and about Feldman, clippings, programs, and photographs.
C. F. Peters Collection of Morton Feldman Manuscripts, 1961-1969
Mus. Arc. 2.4
The collection consists of 79 works by Morton Feldman in either score or part formats (72 scores; 7 sets of parts). All but one item are ink manuscripts on vellum. These served as the masters that Feldman submitted to C. F. Peters and Peters published directly from these masters.